### Max Brooks - C.V

**Address:** 4 Normanby Rd **Phone:** 07519 581 052

Bristol, BS5 OLA

Email: max@radiallogic.co.uk Date of Birth: 28th May 1986

**Key Skills:** 

ReactJSPHP 7 and 8

MySQL and MongoDB Databases 

O Docker, AWS and Git

Python 3Linux and OSX

## Personal profile:

I'm a full stack engineer with a lot of experience fitting into new environments and picking up new domain language and paradigms. I can apply my experience from multiple industries, team configurations and technical stacks to new environments.

I've specialised in PHP and React.js and more broadly I have skills in AWS, python, Linux, OSX, both MySQL and MongoDB databases and docker. I enjoy problem solving and learning new technologies. I'm working on a node.js, express, typescript and react application for saving information drawn onto maps. I've written about 5,000 lines of typescript so far and I've found it easy to apply my years of backend experience to this project. Access can be provided on request.

Recommendations from previous contracts can be found on linkedin.

# **Employment History:**

Outside IR35 Contract positions.

**HID Global** (October 2022 - April 2023) - Contract senior react developer - I helped design and build a react application to help install and manage biometric access devices. We consumed data from REST APIs and web sockets. I used the latest react development patterns such as custom hooks and modern libraries such as Jotai and react query. I also provided mentoring to more junior developers when required.

**BookingLive** (March 2022 - June 2022) - Contract senior developer - I worked on two projects for bookingLive, I completed maintenance on a headless API written with Laravel and MySQL. I got the full suite of unit tests working and I rewrote a report written in Laravel which took nine hours to run to work in under one minute using MySQL. I also delivered a navigation feature using react hooks and jest snapshots.

**Low6** (January 2022 - March 2022) - Contract senior developer - I delivered data import functionality for an existing rest api and database schema. All my work was unit tested and written in the Laravel framework in PHP 8.

**MotorK** (July 2021 - October 2021) - Contract senior developer - I wrote features for and refactored on a large php API which used Symfony 5.

**Gravitai** (March 2021 - June 2021) - Contract senior developer - I upgraded a legacy booking plugin for a Symfony based platform to work with the latest version. I also completed devops tasks around preparing the upgraded platform for release and wrote some user stories for an ERP project that was being outsourced to india.

**Stablelogic LTD** (September 2020 - February 2021) - Contract senior developer - I used Python 3 to write network testing software running on portable linux devices which connected to AWS IOT. I used a full suite of AWS tools including ECR, EC2, codecommit, IOT and TimeStream databases. I used the Symfony 5 PHP framework and React to build admin and configuration applications.

**Somerset Design** (October 2019 - December 2019) - Contract senior developer - Working for this agency I worked with legacy PHP, Laravel and React with Redux building features for a real estate application. Myself and another contractor were helping to meet a delivery deadline.

**Wessex internet** (June 2018 - September 2019) - Contract principle developer - I managed stakeholders, implemented an agile workflow, and designed and built a business data management and asset mapping application. I used Symfony 4, react, babel, leaflet.js (Leaflet) and mongodb. I used virtual linux boxes for development. After an initial period of three months working in the office in Dorset this role was worked 80% remotely, with just one day a week spent in the office. I used and converted ordnance survey gis data, geoJSON, shapefiles and KML datafiles for this application.

**Superdry** (March 2018 - May 2018) - Contract senior developer - I refactored the existing front end to be responsive and added new language sites to legacy code based in Joomla.

**Ember Interactive** (January 2016 - March 2018) - Multiple freelance roles - I worked on building a react and redux front end for a codeigniter based application. Part of this role included setting up browserify to compile ES6 using babel. On a separate project I worked on a codeigniter ecommerce site utilising a custom RESTful product API.

**Claire's accessories** (January 2017 - May 2017) - This role involved transitioning between SAAS environments in the end it was more business analysis than development. I identified the need for and helped document the system, build a development team and implemented agile methodologies. I also helped fix system architectural problems and worked with a number of external service providers. I was partially involved in the react and redux front end for the new platform. I used azure and AWS in this role.

**Monaco Solicitors** (January 2016 - March 2018) - Multiple freelance roles - Adding features and fixing bugs on a CRM tool built based on wordpress. I used PHP, MySQL, Linux and vagrant in this role.

**Sotic** (January 2016 - March 2018) - Multiple freelance roles - I built a content delivering RESTful API using zend 2, Apigility, BDD with behat and mongodb. I also helped build and maintain the development stack using vagrant and docker. The system was hosted using docker and AWS. We used Agile and DevOps methodologies.

**Mages group** (January 2016 - March 2018) - Multiple freelance roles - I built a simple user editable site written in Symfony. I used MVC PHP, MySQL, Vagrant and Linux for this role.

**Blue Venn** (October 2015 - January 2016) - Contract senior developer - I came in to help finish a large and complicated PHP application which had used Doctrine ORM and Zend framework to manage a huge data set, and help with support tickets for the same project. The project had suffered a major loss of product knowledge due to redundancies and also had lived through major changes in project management. The project was successfully completed to the timescale that was set out when I arrived.

Below are permanent positions

Head of IT at Impossible Camera (Berlin)

September 2014 - March 2015

After a month of working for Impossible, I was promoted to lead developer and after another two months to Head of IT. Impossible is a rapidly growing company with offices in NYC, Berlin, Enschede and Vienna. My main responsibility here was to manage a team of developers and IT administrators that worked on the internal ERP system and the associated e-commerce site which it supported. This involved prioritising tasks and managing an iterative DevOps/agile process.

I interviewed and hired technical staff members. I also modified the existing software delivery process to reflect business requirements and improve QA. I added extra statuses to our project management software (Redmine) to reduce confusion between stakeholders. I also changed the development environment from using MAMP to Vagrant to reduce the risk of problems stemming from developing on a system which was different to the live platform. This also sped up the setup of new development environments.

I was involved with planning a replacement ERP system. This involved understanding business processes and requirements gathering.

#### Software Engineer at Helastel (Bristol)

November 2012 - August 2014

My main role here was developing a custom ERP system using the PHP framework Codelgniter. I was heavily involved in requirements gathering and worked with external clients to develop specifications and wire frames. I was the technical lead on the main project I worked on, this involved defining the architecture of the application and implementing it. I was part of the team that defined how we would work with our client in terms of scoping, estimation, delivery and QA.

#### Web Developer at ITC Compliance (Bristol)

September 2011 - June 2012

My main project was developing a complex user script editing system using a large OO PHP code base built on top of legacy procedural code. This project involved a fair amount of AJAX and jQuery for the user interface and some fairly complex MySQL for the back end. I also developed a workaround for multi-threading in PHP which we used to manage the transcoding of video using ffmpeg.

#### Systems Administrator at Aupix Ltd (Bristol)

December 2009 - March 2011

I was responsible for setting up and maintaining Linux servers which were mostly virtual machines. I used python 2.7 to automate simple tasks and test the core application. I removed several overlapping documentation and client communication systems and replaced them with the project management software redmine. I also installed and configured modified versions of the VoIP PBX asterisk. I used and gained experience with administration tools like Nagios, puppet and SVN.

#### Web Application Developer at Imperium (Bristol)

March 2009 - December 2009

Most of my time was spent designing and implementing OOP PHP5 applications and supporting legacy web applications. There was an almost complete lack of documentation and domain knowledge, this meant I developed code and database analysis skills. I was also responsible for the server maintenance and code releases.

#### Web Developer at Legatio Technologies (Swindon)

March 2008 - March 2009

My work here was very varied, which included designing and implementing a VoIP telephone network, server administration, javascript, perl scripts, MySQL and PHP. The majority of my time was spent developing a large application which was written in a mixture of object oriented PHP4 and PHP5 with a MySQL database. This project also involved Javascript, XSLT and HTML.

Non IT Jobs:

August 2005 - February 2008

I worked for several bars and restaurants during this period, all the time working on open source projects and expanding my knowledge of computer systems.

**Coyle Timber Products:** 

February 2004 - September 2005

I worked for Coyle Timber Products as a Green Oak Woodworker. I also supported the few office computers when necessary. I took five months unpaid leave from this job to travel in Southeast Asia.

Carpenter Oak and Woodland Products:

July 2001 - January 2004

I trained and worked as a Green Oak Woodworker. Using a draw-knife and a hydraulic splitter to produce drawn pegs, dowels, shingles and tile pegs.

**Education and Qualifications:** 

1997 - 2001: The Corsham School

**GNVQ Information and Communication Technology** 

6 GCSEs including English, Mathematics, and Science

Interests and hobbies:

I love paragliding, music and rock climbing.